爸爸
Baba...
什麼事 兒子
Yes, my son.
跟我講個故事吧
Tell me a story.
什麼故事
Which one?
關於家鄉的故事
The story of home.
數百萬年前
Millions of years ago...
一塊振金隕石撞向地球
a meteorite made of vibranium...
振金是宇宙中最為堅硬的物質
the strongest substance in the universe...
隕石最終落在了非洲大陸上..
struck the continent of Africa...
影響改變了周圍的植被
affecting the plant life around it.
待到人類的時代來臨
And when the time of man came...
五個部落定居在此並稱此地為 瓦坎達
five tribes settled on it and called it Wakanda.
這些部落之間經常爆發戰爭
The tribes lived in constant war with each other...
直到一位戰鬥巫師
until a warrior shaman...
見到了來自黑豹女神芭絲特的幻影
received a vision from the Panther Goddess Bast...
引領他找到了心形草
who led him to the Heart-Shaped Herb...
一種能賦予他超越人類的力量
a plant that granted him
速度和直覺的植物
superhuman strength, speed and instincts.
這名勇士成為了國王...
The warrior became king...
也是第一代黑豹
and the first Black Panther...
瓦坎達的守護者
the protector of Wakanda.
四個部落都接受了國王的統治
Four tribes agreed to live under the king's rule...
只有賈巴裏部落孤居在雪嶺之間
but the Jabari Tribe isolated themselves in the mountains.
瓦坎達人民利用振金發展科技
The Wakandans used vibranium to develop technology...
比全世界所有國家都先進
more advanced than any other nation.
然而隨著瓦坎達的崛起
But as Wakanda thrived...
它周圍的世界卻陷入了更深的混亂
the world around it descended further into chaos.
為了保證振金的安全
To keep vibranium safe...
瓦坎達人民決意要隱匿於世
the Wakandans vowed to hide in plain sight...
不向外界展露
keeping the truth of their power
他們真實的力量
from the outside world.
我們還在潛伏麼 爸爸
And we still hide, Baba?
是的
Yes.
為什麼
Why?
- 運氣球  - 才不是運氣
- Lucky shot! - That ain't lucky!
- 隨便吧  - 一邊去
Whatever! Get outta here!
注意
Check up.
過來 防守他
Pick your man up! He open.
怎麼著
Where you at?
快上  快上  快上
Let's go, let's go, let's go.
傳球 傳球
Pass! Pass!
- 我就知道 - 快點啊
- Got you, E. - E, hurry up!
看我的
Watch me get this.
蒂姆·哈達威流  這招就該這麼叫
Tim Hardaway style. That's what I call it, baby.
來啊
Come on.
你怎麼樣
What you got?
你拿我沒轍
You ain't got nothing.
聽著 我們只要保證快進快出
Hey, look, if we get in and out quick,
就沒什麼好擔心的
won't be no worries.
你開車從西邊過來
You in the van, come in through from the west.
轉到街角處
Come around the corner.
就停在這
- Land right here. - Mmm-hmm.
我跟雙胞胎把車停在這
Me and the twins are pulling up right here.
這車就不要了 明白嗎 我們從這兒…
We're leaving this car behind, okay? We come this...
把槍收起來
Hide the straps.
是警察嗎
Yo, is it the Feds?
不是
No.
兩個長得和格蕾絲·瓊斯一樣的妞
It's these two Grace Jones-looking chicks.
還帶著矛
They're holding spears.
開門
Open it.
你確定？
You serious?
她們下次就不是敲門了
They won't knock again.
你是誰
Who are you?
恩喬布王子  阿祖裏之子
Prince N'Jobu, son of Azzuri.
向我證明你是我們的一員
Prove to me you are one of us.
陛下
My King.
退下
Leave us.
這是詹姆斯 我以生命擔保他值得信任 他可以留下
This is James. I trust him with my life. He stays...
只要您允許的話  特查卡國王
with your permission, King T'Chaka.
如你所願
As you wish.
起來吧
At ease.
過來  兄弟
Come, baby brother.
讓我看看你過得怎樣
Let me see how you are holding up.
看你體格很棒嘛
You look strong.
女神保佑 我很健康
Glory to Bast, I am in good health.
家裏怎麼樣？
How is home?
不怎麼樣
Not so good.
兄弟
Baby brother.
我們家鄉遭到了襲擊
There has been an attack.
這個人...
This man...
叫尤利西斯·克勞...
Ulysses Klaue...
偷了我們0.25噸的振金
stole a quarter ton of vibranium from us...
為了逃跑 他還在邊境地區引爆了炸彈
and triggered a bomb at the border to escape.
我們死傷慘重
Many lives were lost.
他知道我們藏置振金的地點...
He knew where we hid the vibranium...
也知道如何有效發動襲擊
and how to strike.
他有內應
He had someone on the inside.
那你來這裏做什麼？
Why are you here?
因為我想讓你看著我的眼睛
Because I want you to look me in the eyes...
告訴我你為什麼要背叛瓦坎達
and tell me why you betrayed Wakanda.
我沒有背叛祖國
I did no such thing.
告訴他你是誰
Tell him who you are.
巴杜之子 祖瑞
Zuri, son of Badu...
什麼？
What?
詹姆斯 詹姆斯 你騙了我？
James. James, you lied to me?
放開他
Leave him.
你一直都是瓦坎達人的臥底？
You were Wakandan this whole time?
你背叛了瓦坎達
You betrayed Wakanda!
你怎麼可以欺騙我？
How could you lie to me like...
住手
Stand down.
你以為我們只派了你一個間諜到這裏嗎？
Did you think that you were the only spy we sent here?
恩喬布王子
Prince N'Jobu...
我命令你即刻回國...
you will return home at once...
你將會面對議會的質詢
where you will face the Council...
並向他們坦白你的罪行
and inform them of your crimes.
開球吧
Check up!
防好你的人 防好你的人
Guard your man, guard your man!
非洲小國瓦坎達正舉行全國哀悼
The tiny nation of Wakanda
逝世的特查卡國王
is mourning the death of its monarch, King T'Chaka.
一周前 這位深受愛戴的統治者
The beloved ruler was one of many confirmed dead...
在聯合國總部
after a terrorist attack
的恐怖襲擊中喪生
at the United Nations a week ago.
他是眾多遇難者中的一位
The suspect has since been apprehended.
嫌疑人現已被逮捕
Though it remains one of
即使瓦坎達是世界上最窮的國家之一
the poorest countries in the world...
國內山巒起伏
fortified by mountain ranges...
雨林密佈
and an impenetrable rainforest...
但該國從未參與過國際貿易
Wakanda does not engage
也從未接受過國際援助
in international trade or accept aid.
繼承該國王位的人
The succession of the throne...
會是前國王
is expected to fall to the oldest
的長子
of the king's two children...
也就是特查拉王子
Prince T'Challa.
王子殿下...
My Prince...
我們就要到達他們上空了
coming up on them now.
沒事的 奧科燁 我自己能解決
No need, Okoye. I can handle this alone.
嗯
Hmm.
我會盡快把娜奇雅救出來
I will get Nakia out as quickly as possible.
你見到她時 不要愣住就好
Just don't freeze when you see her.
你在說什麼？
What are you talking about?
我可不會愣
I never freeze.
發生什麼了？
What's going on?
發動機壞了 不能啟動了
It's the car. It lost power. It won't start.
這車開不動了
The car no start.
什麼情況？
What happened?
引擎壞了
The engine failed.
我們的也是
Ours, too.
上尉 這是什麼？
What is it, Captain?
防禦陣型
Defense positions.
有人攻擊我們嗎？
Are we under attack?
防禦陣型
Defense positions.
恩喬 到那邊去
Get around to the side.
防禦陣型
Defense positions.
嘿 防禦陣型
Hey. Defense positions!
不要耍花招
No games.
你們看到了什麼？
What do you see?
來了 來了
Come in. Come in.
- 那邊  - 注意後方
Over there! Look back!
當心
Watch out!
特查拉 不要
T'Challa, no!
他還是個孩子
This one's just a boy.
他也是被拐騙了
He got kidnapped as well.
娜奇雅
Nakia...
我
I...
- 我想..  - 嘿
- I wanted... - Hey!
- 她在我手裏 - 不許動 否則我就開槍了
I have her! Don't move! I will shoot!
我會馬上開槍的
I will shoot her right now.
你還是愣住了
You froze.
啊
Ah...
你為什麼來這？ 你壞了我的任務
Why are you here? You've ruined my mission.
我父親去世了 娜奇雅
My father is dead, Nakia.
明天我將加冕為王
I will be crowned king tomorrow.
我希望你明天能到場
And I wish for you to be there.
你們自己回家吧
Carry yourselves home now.
謝謝你
Thank you.
帶上這個男孩 把他送回他的族人身邊
And take the boy. Get him to his people.
謝謝你
Thank you oh.
今天的事你們不許對任何人說
You will speak nothing of this day.
好
Yes.
謝謝
Thank you.
娜奇雅姐姐
Sister Nakia...
王子殿下
My Prince...
我們到家了
we are home.
看多少次都不會膩
This never gets old.
母后
Queen Mother...
公主
Princess...
請您節哀順變
My comfort for your loss.
謝謝你 娜奇雅
Thank you, Nakia.
你能回來真是太好了
It is so good to have you back with us.
帶她去河畔
Take her to the River Province
為典禮做準備
to prepare her for the ceremony.
是 將軍
Yes, General.
他是不是愣住了？
Did he freeze?
像被車燈嚇住的羚羊一樣
Like an antelope in headlights.
你說完了嗎？
Are you finished?
沒想到我妹妹在大典日子前
So surprised my little sister came
親自來接我
to see me off before our big day.
你想得美
You wish!
我是為了脈衝珠來的 我要給珠子做個升級
I'm here for the EMP beads. I've developed an update.
升級？不了吧 珠子挺好使的
Update? No. It worked perfectly.
你還要我教你多少次？
How many times do I have to teach you?
不能因為一件工具目前能正常使用
Just because something works
就覺得它不需要得到改進
doesn't mean that it cannot be improved.
你在教我？ 你知道什麼？
You are teaching me? What do you know?
知道的比你多
More than you.
我倒要看看你的儀式禮服
I can't wait to see what kind of update you make...
能升級成什麼樣
to your ceremonial outfit.
舒莉
Shuri!
對不起 媽媽
Sorry, Mother!
今天你感覺如何？ 媽媽
How are you feeling today, Mama?
驕傲
Proud.
我和你父親將永遠記得這一天
Your father and I would talk about this day all the time.
他與我們同在...
He is with us...
現在該你繼位稱王了
and it is your time to be king.
早上好
Good morning.
需要幫助嗎？
How can I help you?
哦 就隨便看看這些工藝品
I was just checking out these artifacts.
他們告訴我你是這方面的專家
They tell me you're the expert.
你可以這麼說
Ah. You could say that.
它們很漂亮
They're beautiful.
這是從哪兒來的？
Where's this one from?
波波阿善提部落
The Bobo Ashanti tribe...
也就是現在的加納
present day Ghana...
十九世紀的產物
19th century.
真的嗎？
For real?
那麼這個呢？
What about this one?
這個來自貝寧的埃多族
That one's from the Edo people of Benin...
十六世紀的
16th century.
那你再和我說說這個
Now, tell me about this one.
也是來自貝寧 七世紀的產物
Also from Benin, seventh century.
我想 應該是富拉部落
Fula tribe, I believe.
不對
Nah.
你說什麼？
I beg your pardon?
表面上看來 它是被英國士兵從貝寧掠走的
It was taken by British soldiers in Benin
其實它來自瓦坎達
but it's from Wakanda.
它是用振金製成的
And it's made out of vibranium.
不用多說了
Don't trip.
這個東西我從你這收了
I'mma take it off your hands for you.
這些東西是不出售的
These items aren't for sale.
你認為你的祖先是怎麼得到這些東西的呢？
How do you think your ancestors got these?
你覺得他們是用合理的價錢買下來的？
You think they paid a fair price?
還是直接奪走了它 就像他們奪走其它所有東西那樣？
Or did they take it, like they took everything else?
先生 我必須...
Sir, I'm going to have to
請你離開這裏了
ask you to leave.
從我一進來
You got all this security in here
你就已經讓所有安保人員盯著我了
watching me ever since I walked in.
但你忘了檢查
But you ain't checking for
你自己吃進肚子裏的東西
what you put in your body.
好了 夥計 走吧
All right, mate. Let's have it.
快點 夥計 別磨蹭了
Come on, mate. Time.
我覺得她好像不大對勁
I think she might not be feeling too good.
嘿 快找人幫忙 這裏
Somebody get some help! Come here!
快叫醫生 嘿 誰快來幫忙一下
Call a doctor, please! Please, somebody, come help!
這裏需要緊急救護
Medical emergency right away
西非展區 請馬上過來
in the West African Exhibit, please, right away.
當心
Look out.
大家請後退 配合一下 謝謝
Step back, please. Step back. Thank you.
醫生來了 醫生來了
Coming through over there. Medics coming through.
我去休息一下
I'm gonna take a break.
請為這位女士讓讓路
Let's give the lady some space, please.
請退後 先生們
Step back, please, gents.
請退後
Step back, please.
嘿 過來
Hey, come here.
過來 過來 別害怕
Come here. It's okay.
你可以走了 但不要告訴任何人 好嗎？
You can go, but just don't tell anyone, all right?
老兄 你為什麼不直接在這裏開槍呢？
Bro, why you ain't just shoot him right here?
因為犯罪現場
Because it's better to leave
越分散越好
the crime scene more spread out.
讓這案子看起來像是外行人做的
Makes us look like amateurs.
那現在呢 我們來看看
Now then, let's see if you know
你是不是真的懂行
what you're talking about.
這只是開胃菜
That's just a taste.
你發財了 小子
You're gonna be a rich boy.
那你最好把它快點賣掉
You better sell that quick.
已經賣出去了
It's already sold!
不管你有什麼意圖
Whatever you try,
瓦坎達人可能會出現
the Wakandans'll probably show up.
那今天我可要爽了
That'll make my day.
我可以一石二鳥
I can kill two birds with one stone.
你不是想跟我說那也是振金吧？
You're not telling me that's vibranium, too?
不是 我只是在感受這個面具
Nah, I'm just feeling it.
前進
Onward!
我 祖瑞
I, Zuri...
巴杜之子..
son of Badu...
向各位介紹
give to you...
特查拉王子
Prince T'Challa...
黑豹
the Black Panther!
王子殿下
The prince...
現將黑豹之力
will now have the strength of the Black Panther...
移除
stripped away.
願祖上榮光永存
Praise the ancestors.
在儀式戰鬥中
Victory in ritual combat...
勝利來自另一方的投降或者死亡
comes by yield or death.
如果哪個部落有意派出勇士出戰
If any tribe wishes to put forth a warrior...
那我現在就向他指明
I now offer...
通向王位之路
a path to the throne.
商人部落今天不參加王位挑戰
The Merchant Tribe will not challenge today.
邊疆部落今天不參加王位挑戰
The Border Tribe will not challenge today.
河流部落今天不參加王位挑戰
The River Tribe will not challenge today.
山礦部落今天不參加王位挑戰
The Mining Tribe will not challenge today.
還有哪位具有皇族血統的人
Is there any member of a royal blood...
想參加王位挑戰的嗎？
who wishes to challenge for the throne?
這個緊身內衣實在是太不舒服了
This corset is really uncomfortable...
既然沒人挑戰 我們還是收拾收拾各回各家好吧？
so could we all just wrap it up and go home?
媽媽
Mother!
- 他們是賈巴裏部落的？ - 是的
- Are they Jabari? - Yes.
姆巴庫 你來這幹什麼？
M'Baku, what are you doing here?
今天是王位挑戰日
It's challenge day.
我們從深山裏觀察你們
We have watched...
聆聽你們
and listened from the mountains!
看看你們這樣子 我們感到厭惡
We have watched with disgust...
因為你們居然讓一個小毛孩子
as your technological advancements
來監管你們那些先進科技
have been overseen by a child!
她蔑視傳統
Who scoffs at tradition!
現在你們還要把王位
And now you want to hand the nation
交給這個連父王
over to this prince...
都保護不了的王子手上
who could not keep his own father safe.
不是嗎？
Mmm?
我們可不接受
We will not have it.
我說 我們不接受
I said, we will not have it, oh!
我 姆巴庫...
I, M'Baku...
賈巴裏部落的領袖
leader of the Jabari...
我接受你的挑戰 姆巴庫
I accept your challenge, M'Baku.
願哈姆曼的榮光永存
Glory to Hanuman.
賈巴裏人就位
Jabari!
多拉米拉吉護衛隊
Dora Milaje!
前進
Onward!
王位挑戰開始
Let the challenge begin!
哦
Oh!
站起來
Stand up!
來啊
Come!
特查拉
T'Challa!
現在你的神在哪?
Where is your god now?
是的
Yes!
沒力氣
No powers.
沒爪子
No claws.
沒有特製戰服
No special suit, oh!
就是一個普通人 不適合領導我們
Just a boy not fit to lead!
給他看你是誰
Show him who you are!
我是特查拉王子
I am Prince T'Challa...
特查拉國王的兒子
son of King T'Chaka!
你可以做到的 特查拉
You can do this, T'Challa!
打的好
Yes!
加油
Come on!
投降吧 別逼我殺你
Yield! Don't make me kill you.
我寧願死
I would rather die!
特查拉
T'Challa!
你已帶著榮譽而戰
You have fought with honor!
現在投降吧 你的子民需要你
Now yield! Your people need you.
特查拉
T'Challa!
投降 兄弟
Yield, man!
特查拉
T'Challa!
好的
Yes! Yes!
現在我向各位宣佈
I now present to you...
特查拉成功繼承王位
King T'Challa...
黑豹
the Black Panther.
祖瑞
Zuri.
國王陛下
My King.
瓦坎達萬歲
Wakanda forever!
讓這個心形草
Allow the Heart-Shaped Herb...
恢復黑豹的力量
to restore the powers of the Black Panther...
帶你前往先祖的世界
and take you to the Ancestral Plane.
特查卡
T'Chaka...
我們向您發起召喚
we call on you.
來這見您的兒子
Come here to your son.
願祖上榮光永存
Praise the ancestors.
父親
Father.
我的兒子
My son.
對不起
I'm sorry.
站起來
Stand up.
你是一個國王
You are a king.
怎麼了？ 兒子
What is wrong my son?
我還沒準備好
I am not ready.
你這一生不是
Have you not prepared
都在為當上國王做準備嗎?
to be king your whole life?
你不是一直在我身邊
Have you not trained and studied,
訓練 學習嗎？
been by my side?
我指的不是這個
That is not what I am talking about.
我還是接受不了沒有你的日子
I am not ready to be without you.
一個男人如果沒有讓
A man who has not prepared his children
他的兒子坦然面對父親的離世
for his own death...
那他就是一位失敗的父親
has failed as a father.
我有讓你失望過嗎？
Have I ever failed you?
從來沒有
Never.
請告訴我如何才能守護好瓦坎達
Tell me how to best protect Wakanda.
我希望成為一個偉大的國王 爸爸
I want to be a great king, Baba.
就像你一樣
Just like you.
你會面臨很多困難
You're going to struggle.
所以你要任用
So you'll need to surround yourself
自己信任的人
with people you trust.
你是一個好男人 同時也有著一顆善良的心
You're a good man with a good heart.
對於一個好人來說 當國王很艱難
And it's hard for a good man to be king.
呼吸
Breathe.
特查拉 呼吸
T'Challa, breathe.
呼吸
Breathe.
他在那
He was there.
他就在那 我的父親
He was there. My father.
只要一個
Just one?
回家吧 娜奇雅
Come home, Nakia.
我就在家啊
I'm right here.
留下來
Stay.
我來是對你表示支持 和悼念你的父親的
I came to support you and to honor your father...
但我不能留下來
but I can't stay.
外面的世界需要我
I found my calling out there.
我見過太多人對需要幫助的人視而不見
I've seen too many in need just to turn a blind eye.
我留在這是不會快樂的
I can't be happy here...
因為我心裏總會惦記著那些一無所有的人
knowing that there's people out there who have nothing.
你希望瓦坎達做什麼呢？
What would you have Wakanda do about it?
分享我們的科技
Share what we have.
我們可以提供援助
We could provide aid...
和技術支持
and access to technology
為那些需要的人提供庇護
and refuge to those who need it.
其他國家也在做 我們可以做的更棒
Other countries do it, we could do it better.
我們與這些國家是不同的 娜奇雅
We are not like these other countries, Nakia.
如果世界瞭解了我們的真相
If the world found out what we truly are...
知道我們所擁有的一切
what we possess...
我們將會失去原有的生活
we could lose our way of life.
瓦坎達足夠強大 幫助其他人的同時
Wakanda is strong enough to help others
也能夠保護自己
and protect ourselves at the same time.
如果你不那麼固執己見 會是一個偉大的皇后
If you were not so stubborn, you would make a great queen.
正因為固執 我才能成為一個偉大的皇后
I would make a great queen because I am so stubborn.
- 噢 你看你已經承認了 - 如...如果我想當的話
- Ah! See, you admit it! - If that's what I wanted.
是他嗎？
Is that him?
女神保佑 他還在長大嗎
Glory to Bast, man. Is he still growing?
當然
Of course.
我看到娜奇雅回來了
I see Nakia is back.
你們倆會復合嗎？
You guys going to work it out?
特查拉
T'Challa...
怎麼了？
what's wrong?
娜奇雅認為我們應該做更多的事
Nakia thinks we should be doing more.
比如說？
More, like what?
對外援助 難民項目
Foreign aid, refugee programs.
如果你讓難民涌入
You let the refugees in...
他們的麻煩也會跟著進來
they bring their problems with them.
之後瓦坎達就會變得像其他地方一樣
And then Wakanda is like everywhere else.
如果現在你要我和我的將士們一起
Now if you said you wanted me and my men...
走出國門 蕩盡世間不平事
to go out there and clean up the world,
那我也必定全力以赴
then I'll be all for it.
但是就這麼向其他國家發動過戰爭
But waging war on other countries
不是我們的行事風格
has never been our way.
你的也響了？
You, too, huh?
天呀 我們有麻煩了
Bast! We're in trouble.
國王陛下
My King.
我的愛人
My love.
你肯定猜不到我們在雷達裏發現了誰
You will never guess who just popped up on our radar.
一件瓦坎達王國手工藝品 曾被誤認為是其他文明的手工製品
A misidentified Wakandan artifact...
昨天被人從一家英國博物館盜走
was stolen yesterday from a British museum.
我們得知尤利西斯·克勞
We have learned Ulysses Klaue...
計劃把那件振金製品
plans to sell the vibranium to an American buyer...
在韓國出售給一位美國買家
in South Korea...
交易時間是明天晚上
tomorrow night.
近30年來 我們一直沒能抓到克勞
Klaue has escaped our pursuits for almost 30 years.
沒有抓到他 或許是我父親最大的遺憾
Not capturing him is, perhaps, my father's greatest regret.
我希望把克勞帶回來接受審判
I wish to bring Klaue back here to stand trial.
瓦坎達王國現在需要的不是一個戰士
Wakanda does not need a warrior right now.
我們需要一個國王
We need a king.
我的父母在他的襲擊中喪生
My parents were killed when he attacked.
我每天都在想著
Not a day goes by when I do not think
克勞從我們這奪走的一切
about what Klaue took from us.
他從我身上奪去的那些
From me.
這麼好的機會 怎能錯過
It's too great an opportunity to pass.
把我帶上
Take me with you.
我們並肩作戰一起把他拿下
We'll take him down together, side by side.
我需要你在這保護邊疆
I need you here protecting the border.
那我得問一句
Then I ask...
你是當場殺了他呢
you kill him where he stands...
還是把他帶回到我們這呢？
or you bring him back to us.
我向你保證
You have my word.
我會把帶回來
I will bring him back.
我們就這麼干
We will proceed with the mission.
國王陛下
My King!
別這樣 別這樣
Stop it. Stop it.
我已經幫你往釜山提前送了一輛車過去
I've already sent a car ahead to Busan for you.
你要帶誰和你一起去韓國？
Who are you taking with you to Korea?
奧科燁
Okoye.
還有娜奇雅
And Nakia as well.
你確定帶前女友執行任務是個好主意？
You sure it's a good idea to take your ex on a mission?
是的
Yes.
我們會沒事的
We'll be fine.
而且你要隨時待命 我們需要支援
Besides, you'll be on call should we need backup.
太棒了
Yes!
我給你看些好東西 哥哥
I have great things to show you, Brother.
這是你到韓國用的通訊設備
Here are your communication devices for Korea.
無限範圍
Unlimited range,
還裝備有音頻監控系統
also equipped with audio surveillance system.
看看這些
Check these out.
遠程控制的基莫由珠
Remote access Kimoyo Beads.
升級過的界面直接和我的沙盤相連
Updated to interface directly with my sand table.
啊
Ah.
這些是什麼？
And what are these?
真正的問題應該是 你穿的是什麼？！
The real question is what are those?
為什麼你要在我的實驗室裏露出腳趾？
Why do you have your toes out in my lab?
什麼？你不喜歡我的皇家涼鞋？
What, you don't like my royal sandals?
我上任第一天想走復古路線
I wanted to go old school for my first day.
好吧 我估計長老們會喜歡你這裝束的
I bet the Elders loved that.
穿上試試
Try them on.
全自動的
Fully automated.
就像爸爸常看的美國老電影
Like the old American movie Baba used to watch.
嗯
Mmm.
我研製的鞋具有完美吸音特性
And I made them completely sound absorbent.
有意思
Interesting.
猜我怎麼叫它們
Guess what I call them.
運動鞋
Sneakers.
因為你...
Because you...
當我沒說
Never mind.
如果你想活捉克勞
If you're going to take on Klaue...
你就需要設計團隊提供給你的最尖端裝備
you'll need the best the design group has to offer.
看這第一件戰服
Exhibit A.
- 這是我設計的 - 過時的技術
- My design. - Old tech.
- 很老嗎？ - 能湊合用 但還是太過時了
- Old? - Functional, but old.
「嘿 有人向我開槍
"Hey, people are shooting at me.
等一下 讓我先戴上頭盔」
"Wait, let me put on my helmet."
夠了吧
Enough.
現在 瞧瞧這些
Now, look at these.
你喜歡那件嗎？
Do you like that one?
很吸引人
Tempting.
但是金色太顯眼 不夠低調
But the idea is to not be noticed.
我要這件
This one.
現在讓戰服展示完整形態
Now tell it to go on.
哇哦
Ooh!
整個戰服都集成在牙齒項鏈上
The entire suit sits within the teeth of the necklace.
打它一下
Strike it.
- 打哪都行？ - 是的
- Anywhere? - Mmm-hmm.
天哪 別這麼用力
Not that hard, genius!
你讓我打的 你又沒說用多大力度
You told me to strike it. You didn't say how hard.
我邀請你來我的實驗室
I invite you to my lab,
你卻到處搞破壞嗎？
and you just kick things around?
好吧 或許你該把它做的更牢固些
Well, maybe you should make it a little stronger.
嘿
Hey.
等一下
Wait a minute.
戰服內的納米機器人會吸收動能
The nanites absorb the kinetic energy...
動能會被儲存於戰服內 便於戰服再次使用
and hold it in place for redistribution.
很棒
Very nice.
你再打一下剛才的地方
Strike it again in the same spot.
你在錄像？
You're recording?
科研需要嘛
For research purposes.
刪除那段錄像
Delete that footage.
這邊
This way.
芭斯特女神的旨意 行動會很快結束
Bast willing, this will go quickly...
然後我好摘掉這該死的假髮
and I can get this ridiculous thing off my head.
挺好看的啊  你時不時前後甩甩頭髮
It looks nice. Just whip it back and forth.
什麼？ 那太丟臉了
What? It's a disgrace.
你好 索菲亞
Hello Sophia.
很高興見到你
Good to see you.
這兩個人是誰？
Who are these two?
是我肯尼亞那邊的朋友 超級有錢的 人很不錯
My friends from Kenya. Very deep pockets. They're good.
惹麻煩的本事也很不錯吧...
Good for trouble...
就跟你一樣
...like you?
謝謝
Thank you!
分開行動
Spread out.
買家可能已經到這了
The buyer is likely already here.
剛剛外面的女人
The woman outside.
她說的「麻煩」指的是什麼？
What trouble was she referring to?
我曾與某些象牙商
Ah... I got into a disagreement
幹了一架
with some ivory traders.
- 惹了點小麻煩 - 這樣啊
- Made a bit of a mess. - Hmm.
那麼今晚會有麻煩嗎？
And will there be any trouble tonight,
富有的肯尼亞繼承人小姐
Ms. Kenyan Heiress?
這取決於...
Depends...
我們完成任務的速度
on how quickly we finish the mission.
你們倆專注點好不好？
Can we please focus?
謝謝
Thank you.
這邊
Over here.
來一杯威士忌
One whiskey, please.
注意 有美國人
Eyes up. Americans.
我發現三個
I count three.
是五個
Five.
你怎麼能無視你身後
How could you miss Greased Lightning
的美國佬呢？
there behind you?
六個
Six.
我剛剛發現了一個就職於中央情報局的老朋友
Just spotted an old friend who works for the CIA.
事情變得有點複雜了
It just got a little more complicated.
羅斯探員
Agent Ross.
國王陛下
Your Highness.
你要和克勞做交易？
You are buying from Klaue.
我是代表美國政府
What I'm doing or not doing...
做什麼不做什麼
on behalf of the U.S. government
不用你操心
is none of your concern.
不管你要做什麼...
Now, whatever the hell you're up to...
算幫我個忙 別來礙我的事
do me a favor, stay out of my way.
是我把澤莫交給你的
I gave you Zemo.
我不是也對你的秘密一直保持沉默嗎？
Didn't I keep it under wraps...
你說的是你一個第三世界國家的國王
that the king of a third world country
穿著防彈豹服在外面跑來跑去這個秘密 對吧？
runs around in a bulletproof cat suit?
其實我們彼此彼此
I'd say we were even.
你現在就應該離開這
You really need to leave, now.
我會把克勞一起帶走的
Klaue is leaving out that door with me.
我可警告你了
You've been warned.
骰子是三點
Three, craps.
嘿 你贏了
Hey, you won!
你知道嗎？
You know what?
我覺得我應該接手
I think I'll just take these...
把它們拿到我這邊來
bring them over here
- 代為保管 - 嗯
- and hold on for safekeeping. - Mmm-hmm.
好了 注意點 瓦坎達國王在這裏
Okay, heads up. The king of Wakanda is here.
不能讓他帶走克勞
He cannot leave with Klaue.
好吧
All right.
關於索科維亞事件中的振金
Vibranium from the attack on Sokovia
線索都指向了一個人
links back to a person...
雖然我不會明著承認
that I'm not actually saying
可我是來跟這個人做交易的
I'm here to make a deal with...
而這筆交易是必須進行的
but that deal will not be called off.
所以當事情水落石出的時候
When the dust settles,
你和我可以一起解決這件事
you and me can work something out.
我可不是來這做交易的
I'm not here to make a deal.
克勞 還帶了八個人來
Klaue, plus eight!
將軍那邊呢
General.
已就位 保證我們的撤退路線安全
In position to secure our exit.
振金呢？
And the vibranium?
我還沒有看到
I don't see it yet.
我記得這裏是不許帶武器進來的吧
I thought there were no weapons allowed in here.
確實是這樣
There's not supposed to be.
有些人不聽話
Somebody did not get the memo.
絕對是帶著傢伙呢
Definitely armed.
哼 你這些隨從還挺像樣的嘛
Well, that is quite the entourage.
你這陣容是要出混音唱片嗎？
You got a mixtape coming out?
對 沒錯 實話說我還真有一個
Oh, yeah. Yeah, actually, there is one.
如果你想要 我把雲鏈接發給你
I'll send you the SoundCloud link, if you like.
嘿 戴夫 你把那個鏈接...？
Hey, Dave, can you get the link to the tape?
拜託 我不想聽你的什麼音樂
Please, don't make me listen to your music.
我的意思你帶的人太多了
I just meant you got a lot of people with you.
你以為他們是為你準備的？
You think they're for you?
別擔心
Don't worry.
和你交易的只有我一個人
I can do a deal with you all by myself,
非常感謝
thank you very much.
又來了六個人 這是個陷阱
Six more. It's a setup.
鑽石你帶來了吧？
You got the diamonds?
我想這些夠了吧
Okay. That's enough.
- 我們得走了克勞 - 等會兒別動
- We need to move on Klaue. - Stand down.
要是來場槍戰我們可吃不消
We can't afford a shootout.
振金的？
Vibranium?
呃 我本打算買逼格高點的手提箱的 不過...
I was going to buy a fancy suitcase...
我還是想給我自己省點錢
but I thought I'd save myself some money.
就現在 機不可失
It's now or never.
別動
Stand down!
嘿
Hey!
我被識破了
I've been made.
瓦坎達人 是他們
Wakandans! They're here!
- 快撤離此地  - 殺光他們
- Get outta here! - Kill 'em all!
帶上鑽石 快走
Diamonds, quick!
殺人犯
Murderer!
你知道嗎 你跟你老爸可真像
You know, you look just like your old man.
鈔票滿天飛啊
I made it rain!
我們撤吧 老闆
Let's get out of here, boss!
太壯觀了 真刺激
That was awesome! That was awesome!
我們走 快走 快點啊
Let's go! Go, go, go, come on!
- 我們不管他了？ - 他會追上來的
- Do we just leave him? - He'll catch up.
舒莉
Shuri!
太好了 到我登場了
Yes!
遠程駕駛系統已激活
Remote driving system activated.
等等 車在路的哪邊？
Wait! Which side of the road is it?
我的天啊
For Bast's sake!
- 別管了 開就是了 - 好吧 冷靜
- Just drive! - Okay, calm down!
哇哦 出發嘍
Whoo! Let's go!
來點音樂 這麼安靜幹嘛 參加葬禮嗎？
Put some music on. What do you think this is, a funeral?
他在哪輛車上？
Which one is he in now?
嘿 分頭走
Hey, split up!
- 他們想甩掉我們 - 我追右邊那輛
- They're trying to lose us. - I'll take the right.
我們負責另外兩輛 我抄近道去追
We'll take the other two! I see a shortcut.
這我可過不去了
We're not going to make it!
繼續追
Keep going!
哦 哥你厲害
Whoo! Brother!
嘿 那是什麼鬼？
Hey, what was that?
別分心 你做的很好
Don't worry about it. You're doing great.
還開槍呢
Guns.
攻擊手段真原始
So primitive!
那車是振金的 你這蠢貨
It's a vibranium car, you idiots!
子彈打不透
The bullets won't penetrate!
你要幹什麼？
What are you doing?
你開就是了
Just drive.
哦 見鬼
- Whoo! - Shit!
嘿 注意你的戰袍
Hey, look at your suit.
你一直在挨槍子
You've been taking bullets,
戰袍會儲存動能的
charging it up with kinetic energy.
超過那輛車
Pull around the truck.
他去哪兒了？
Where'd he go?
你真秀啊
You show-off.
追上他了
There he is!
抓緊
Hold tight!
好吧 來點刺激的
All right. Let's have some fun!
上車
Hop in.
把矛放後備箱
Put that spear in the trunk.
加速 舒莉
Faster, Shuri.
我已經開到最快了
I'm going as fast as I can!
右轉 右轉
Take a right! Take a right!
不 不 不 不 不
No, no, no!
哥哥
Brother!
克勞
Klaue!
你覺得我們能忘的了嗎？
Did you think we would forget?
看著我 殺人犯
Look at me, murderer!
你從哪裏來搞到這個武器的？
Where did you get this weapon?
你們這種野蠻人不配擁有它
You savages didn't deserve it.
哦 手下留情 國王 手下留情
Oh, mercy, King. Mercy.
你的每一次呼吸都源自我的仁慈
Every breath you take is mercy from me.
國王
King!
全世界都看著呢
The world watches.
來吧 幾位 我們撤 好吧？
Come on. Guys. Let's go, huh?
這就對了
Yeah.
你好啊
Hello.
我能看到你 我能..我能看到你哦
I can see you! I can. I can see you.
這動靜鬧得很大啊
So this is a big mess, huh?
我想我們可以一個唱紅臉 一個唱白臉
I figured we could go good cop, bad cop.
我先和他談 然後你們上
I'll talk to him first, then you guys go in.
我們不能單獨和克勞談
We can't let him talk to Klaue alone.
讓他跟克勞談五分鐘 比在這裏鬧翻要好
Better to let him talk to Klaue alone for 5 minutes than to make a scene here.
你審問完之後
After your questioning,
我們會把他帶回瓦坎達
we will take him back to Wakanda with us.
什麼？ 不 聽著 我很欣賞你
What? No. Look, I like you, a lot.
但他現在是收押在我這 他哪也不能去
But he's in my custody now. He's not going anywhere.
聽著 要不是我幫你們
Listen, I'm doing you guys a favor
你們連這都進不來
by letting you even be in here.
如果他再碰你一次
If he touches you again,
我就把他釘到桌子上
I'm going to impale him to this desk.
她會說英語嗎？
Does she speak English?
她想說的時候才會說
When she wants to.
我進去了
I'm going in.
我結束之後 你們上
When I'm done, you guys are up.
- 特工羅斯  - 怎麼了？
- Agent Ross. - Yeah?
我很感謝你在釜山能幫我們
I do appreciate your help in Busan.
你看見了吧
You see that?
這就叫外交
It's called diplomacy.
不客氣
You're welcome.
-  奧科燁 - 啊啊
Okoye.
客氣點
Play nice.
美國人就這德性
Americans.
你真的不應該信瓦坎達人的話
You know, you really shouldn't trust the Wakandans.
咱倆才是一個步調上的人
I'm much more your speed.
幹我這行的 從不相信任何人
I don't trust anybody, not in this job.
但我感興趣的是那個手臂大炮
But what I am interested in is that arm cannon out there.
你從哪兒拿到的？
Where'd you get that?
那是一個舊的採礦工具 我做了一些改裝
It's an old mining tool that I made some adjustments to.
但是我可以 送你一個 如果你喜歡的話
But I can get you one, if you like.
要不你告訴我你供應商的名字
Why don't you give me the name of your supplier,
然後我去問他們如何？
and I'll ask them.
他就在外面
He's right outside.
你為什麼不親自問問他呢？
Why don't you ask him yourself?
什麼？ 特查拉？
What? T'Challa?
你是想跟我說你手臂上的武器來自瓦坎達？
You're telling me that weapon on your arm is from Wakanda?
對了
Bingo.
你究竟對瓦坎達王國瞭解多少？
What do you actually know about Wakanda?
呃
Um...
牧羊人 紡織品 還有炫酷的衣服
Shepherds, textiles, cool outfits.
這都是表面的東西
It's all a front.
探險家們找了幾個世紀
Explorers searched for it for centuries.
傳說中的黃金之城
El Dorado, the Golden City.
他們以為能在南美洲找到黃金之城
They thought they could find it in South America...
但是其實 黃金之城一直在非洲
but it was in Africa the whole time.
這是一個科技鑄就的奇跡
A technological marvel.
它是以目前人類已知最珍貴的金屬
All because it was built on a mound
為基礎建立起來的
of the most valuable metal known to man.
他們叫它 天賜的禮物
Isipho, they call it. The gift.
也就是振金
Vibranium.
振金 地球上最堅硬的金屬
Vibranium, yeah, strongest metal on earth.
這不僅僅是一種金屬
It's not just a metal.
他們還把它縫進衣服裏
They sew it into their clothes.
振金為他們的城市供能 強化了他們的科技水平
It powers their city, their tech...
幫助他們生產出更強的武器
their weapons.
武器？
Weapons?
是的
Yeah.
我的手臂炮彈和他們的武器比起來跟玩具沒什麼兩樣
Makes my arm cannon look like a leaf blower.
故事編的挺好
That's a nice fairy tale,
但是瓦坎達是第三世界的國家
but Wakanda is a third world country...
而你偷了他們全部的振金
and you stole all their vibranium.
我偷走了...？
I stole...
所有的？
All of it?
我只拿了一點點
I took a tiny piece of it.
他們那裏的振金堆積如山
They have a mountain full of it.
他們已經挖掘了幾千年
They've been mining it for thousands of years...
也不過是挖走了點皮毛而已
and they still haven't scratched the surface.
我是唯一一個見過那景象
I'm the only outsider who's seen it
還能活著回來的外來者
and got out of there alive.
如果你不信我 你去問問你的朋友
If you don't believe me,
他那身衣服是用什麼做的
you ask your friend what his suit is made of.
他那爪子是用什麼做的
What his claws are made of.
你的父親告訴聯合國
Your father told the UN...
克勞偷走了你們所有的振金
that Klaue stole all the vibranium you had.
可現在 他卻說你們手上還有
But now he's telling me you have more.
你相信一個被綁在椅子上的
And you believe the word
軍火商說的話嗎
of an arms dealer strapped to a chair?
那是哪裏
Where is that?
後巷
Back there.
你還隱瞞了什麼
How much more are you hiding?
後面情況不對
Something is happening out back.
趴下
Get down!
Stand down!
找掩護
Cover!
手榴彈
Grenade!
你們不是很從容的嗎
I see you took your time, didn't you?
我的國王
My King!
My King.
娜吉雅
Nakia.
他跳出來 擋在了我前面
He just jumped in front of me.
我覺得他要撐不住了
I don't think he'll make it here.
他的脊柱中槍了
It hit his spine.
給我一顆基莫由珠
Give me a Kimoyo Bead.
這樣應該能穩住一會兒
This will stabilize him for now.
讓我們帶他走
Give him to us.
我們能救他
We can save him.
我們的任務是帶回克勞
Our mission was to bring back Klaue.
我們失敗了
We failed.
這人可是外國情報人員
This man is a foreign intelligence operative.
我們怎麼可以隨便帶他入境
How do we justify bringing him into our borders?
他替我挨了槍
He took a bullet for me.
那是他的選擇
That was his choice.
所以我們就應該見死不救嗎
So now we are just supposed to let him die?
假如說我們救了他
Let us consider that we heal him.
他的職責是向他的國家報告
It is his duty to report back to his country.
而作為國王 你的責任是保護我們
And as king, it is your duty to protect ours.
我非常清楚我的職責 將軍
I'm well aware of my duties, General.
但既然知道我們能救他
I cannot just let him die...
我們就不能眼睜睜地看著他死
knowing we can save him.
我們到底要帶他去哪兒
Where exactly are we taking him?
真棒 又來了一位需要治療的白人了
Great! Another broken white boy for us to fix.
這事真有意思
This is going to be fun.
他會活下來的
He will live.
維卡必來了
W'Kabi is here.
怎麼回事 兄弟 克勞人呢
What's going on, brother? Where is Klaue?
他不在這兒
He's not here.
他從我們眼皮底下溜了
He slipped through our hands.
「溜了」？
"Slipped"?
你父親掌權的三十年間 毫無作為
For 30 years, your father was in power and did nothing.
我以為你掌權後會有所改變
With you, I thought it'd be different.
但似乎沒什麼兩樣
But it's more of the same.
走吧 老大
Let's get going, boss.
你一直把弄來的東西賣給中央情報局的人嗎
You always sell to the CIA?
價高者得
I sell to the highest bidder.
別擔心 等我回到約翰內斯堡後
But don't you worry. When I get back to Joburg...
我會低調一點
and I lay low for a bit,
我保證會付你們薪水的
I'll make sure both you guys get paid.
我不擔心錢 兄弟
Oh, I ain't worried about the money, bro.
我知道你付得起
I know you good for it.
回程時把我們送到瓦坎達就行
On our way back, just drop us off in Wakanda.
你不會想去那裏的 孩子
You don't want to go there, boy.
我已經想好了
Yeah, I do.
放下槍
Drop it!
不然你的小妮子
Or your little Bonnie and Clyde routine
就沒命了
ends today.
立刻放下槍
Put your gun down now!
對不起
I'm sorry.
- 對不起 埃裏克 - 會沒事的
- Sorry, Erik. - It's gonna be okay.
你真的想回瓦坎達嗎
You really want to go to Wakanda?
他們都是野蠻人
They're savages.
這是他們對我們這些人幹的好事
This is what they do to people like us.
我才不在意傷疤呢
I ain't worried about no brand.
給你瞧
Check these out.
每一個都是一條人命
Each one is for a kill.
你可以盡情給自己留下傷疤
You can scar yourself as much as you'd like.
對他們而言 你只是外來者
To them, you'll just be an outsider.
你想踏入那裏 簡直癡心妄想
You're crazy to think that you can walk in there.
我竟然以為你只是個美國瘋子
Ah, to think I saw you as some crazy American.
都退下
Leave us!
所以你沒能按計劃完成任務
So your mission did not go as planned.
當年在我恩喬布叔叔身上發生了什麼
What happened to my uncle N'Jobu?
我父親只是告訴我 他消失了
My father told me he disappeared.
但今天有個男人
There was a man today...
戴著和我手上這枚一樣的戒指
wearing a ring identical to this one.
這不可能
That is not possible.
他從我們手中帶走了克勞 還戴著這枚戒指
He helped Klaue escape from us and he was wearing this ring!
我祖父的戒指！
My grandfather's ring!
別說什麼不可能
Do not tell me what is possible.
告訴我真相
Tell me the truth!
有些真相
Some truths...
沉重得難以承受 特查拉
are too much to bear, T'Challa.
這由不得你來決定
That is not your choice to make.
他怎麼了？
What happened to him?
我答應了國王保守秘密
I promised the king to say nothing.
我才是你的王！
I am your king now!
你叔叔當時在美國
Your uncle took...
執行一項間諜任務
a War Dog assignment in America.
你父親
Your father...
把我安插在那
placed me there...
暗中觀察
to observe...
你父親不知道的是
unbeknownst to him.
你叔叔愛上了一個美國女人
Your uncle fell in love with an American woman.
他們還生了孩子
They had a child.
看到外面世界的苦難
The hardships he saw there...
讓你的叔叔愈發激進
radicalized your uncle.
我觀察了很久
I observed for as long as I could.
他們的總統遭到暗殺
Their leaders have been assassinated.
社區裏充斥著毒品和武器
Communities flooded with drugs and weapons.
我們的黑人同胞受到壓迫 被關進監獄
They are overly policed and incarcerated.
同樣的事情
All over the planet...
在世界各地都在上演
our people suffer because
因為他們沒有武器去還擊
they don't have the tools to fight back.
有了振金武器
With vibranium weapons,
他們便能推翻所有國家
they could overthrow every country...
瓦坎達也能
and Wakanda could rule them all
讓這些國家走上正軌
the right way.
他知道你的父親不會支持
He knew your father would not support this.
所以你叔叔背叛了我們
So, your uncle betrayed us.
不
No!
他幫助克勞竊取振金
He helped Klaue steal the vibranium.
不 不 不
No, no, no.
我命令你即刻回國
You will return home at once...
你將會面對議會的質詢
where you will face the Council...
並向他們坦白你的罪行
and inform them of your crimes.
他拿武器對準我
He drew his weapon on me.
不要
No!
你父親殺了他的親兄弟
Your father killed his own brother...
救了我一命
to save my life.
這件事不要再提起
Speak nothing of this.
那個孩子呢？
And the child?
我們丟下了他
We left him.
我們必須
We had to...
去維持
maintain...
這個謊言
the lie.
這是什麼？
What is this?
只是個小禮物
Just a little gift.
你是什麼人
Who are you?
好吧 這是哪兒？
All right, where am I?
別這麼嚇我 殖民佬
Don't scare me like that, colonizer!
殖什麼？ 我是埃弗雷特
What? My name is Everett.
我知道 埃弗雷特·羅斯
Yes, I know. Everett Ross...
前空軍飛行員 現中央情報局探員
former air force pilot and now CIA.
對
Right.
這裏是瓦坎達嗎
Okay, is this Wakanda?
這是堪薩斯
No, it's Kansas.
韓國的事是什麼時候
How long ago was Korea?
昨天
Yesterday.
我不信
I don't think so.
槍彈傷不會奇跡般地一夜痊癒
Bullet wounds don't just magically heal overnight.
這裏可以
They do here.
但不是靠魔法 而是靠科技
But not by magic, by technology.
別亂碰東西 我哥哥馬上就回來
Don't touch anything. My brother will return soon.
那些火車
These train things...
是磁懸浮列車 對吧
that's magnetic levitation, right?
明顯是
Obviously.
明顯是 但我沒見過這麼...高級的
Obviously, but I've never seen it this efficient.
那些發光板是做什麼用的？
The light panels, what are they?
- 音速穩定器 - 音速啥？
- Sonic stabilizers. - Sonic what?
直接高速運輸
In its raw form...
原始形態的振金
vibranium is too dangerous
過於危險
to be transported at that speed...
所以我設計出了一種方法 暫時鈍化它
so I developed a way to temporarily deactivate it.
那些列車上裝著振金？
There's vibranium on those trains?
這裏到處都有振金
There's vibranium all around us.
你的傷也是它治好的
That's how I healed you.
特查拉在哪
Where is T'Challa?
他把他的基莫由珠關掉了
His Kimoyo Beads have been switched off.
我們不要當跟屁蟲吧 奧科燁
Well, we are not joined at the hip, Okoye.
在邊境出現了一個男人
A man showed up at the border
聲稱自己殺了克勞
who claims to have killed Klaue.
你說什麼
What?
現在維卡必正帶著他前往宮殿
W'Kabi is transporting him, as we speak, to the palace.
我們要找到你的哥哥
We need to find your brother!
一個外來者
An outsider?
不 是瓦坎達人
No, a Wakandan.
他才不是瓦坎達人
He's not a Wakandan.
他跟我一樣是美國人
He's one of ours.
他殺了他的親兄弟
He killed his own brother...
然後還拋下了一個孩子
and left a child behind...
孤身一人
with nothing.
什麼樣的國王...
What kind of king...
什麼樣的人才會做出這樣的事？
What kind of man does that?
人無完人
No man is perfect.
你父親也一樣
Not even your father.
他甚至都沒有好好安葬他
He didn't even give him a proper burial.
我的叔叔恩喬布背叛了我們 但是我的父親...
My uncle N'Jobu betrayed us, but my father...
他犯下的過錯可能更為深重
he may have created something even worse.
嘿
Hey.
看著我
Look at me.
你不能用你父親的罪過來定義你自己
You can't let your father's mistakes define who you are.
你要當一個怎樣的國王得由你自己決定
You get to decide what kind of king you are going to be.
哥哥 你得馬上過來
Brother, you need to get here now!
埃裏克·史蒂文斯
Erik Stevens.
19歲就從安納波利斯大學畢業
Graduated Annapolis age 19...
然後拿到了麻省理工的研究生學位
MIT for grad school.
加入海豹突擊隊後被派往了阿富汗
Joined the SEALs and went straight to Afghanistan...
他在那兒殺人
where he wrapped up confirmed kills,
跟打遊戲似的
like it was a video game.
人們開始叫他 克爾芒戈
Started calling him Killmonger.
他還加入了美國聯合特種作戰司令部的幽靈部隊 這些傢伙可不是鬧著玩的
He joined a JSOC ghost unit. Now these guys are serious.
他們能秘密潛伏
They will drop off the grid...
去執行暗殺
so they can commit assassinations
甚至推翻政府
and take down governments.
他有暴露過他的身份信息嗎？
Did he reveal anything about his identity?
他身上有間諜的紋身
He has a War Dog tattoo...
但是我們資料庫裏沒有他的信息
but we have no record of him.
這個人到底是不是瓦坎達人
Is this man Wakandan or not?
告訴我們這是怎麼回事
Tell us what is going on.
說話
Speak.
我現在站在你們的王宮裏 告訴你們
I'm standing in your house...
我為你們制裁了一個偷了你們振金
serving justice to a man
又謀害了你們人民的人
who stole your vibranium and murdered your people.
你們的國王都沒能制裁他
Justice your king couldn't deliver.
我才不在乎你有沒有把克勞帶回來
I don't care that you brought Klaue.
我到現在還沒有殺你是因為
Only reason I don't kill you where you stand
我知道你是誰
is because I know who you are.
現在 你想要什麼
Now, what do you want?
我想要那王位
I want the throne.
口氣真大
My goodness.
你們都坐在這舒舒服服的
Y'all sittin' up here comfortable.
感覺很好吧
Must feel good.
但全球還有二十億
It's about two billion people
和我們膚色一樣的同胞
all over the world that looks like us.
還活在水深火熱之中
But their lives are a lot harder.
瓦坎達有著能解放他們的工具
Wakanda has the tools to liberate 'em all.
那是什麼工具呢？
And what tools are those?
振金 你們的武器
Vibranium. Your weapons.
我們的武器不是用來向世界發起戰爭的
Our weapons will not be used to wage war on the world.
我們不會拿著振金去當世界警察 去判決 審查
It is not our way to be judge, jury and executioner...
甚至處決 別國的子民的
for people who are not our own.
別國的子民？
Not your own?
但生命不就是從這塊大陸上起源的嗎？
But didn't life start right here on this continent?
全人類不都是你的子民嗎？
So ain't all people your people?
我不是全人類的國王 我是瓦坎達的國王
I am not king of all people. I am king of Wakanda.
而這也是我的責任
And it is my responsibility
保證所有瓦坎達人的安危
to make sure our people are safe...
以及確保振金...
and that vibranium does not fall
不會落入像你這種人的手裏
into the hands of a person like you.
兒子
- Mmm... - Son.
我們陪這個冒牌貨玩得夠久了
We have entertained this charlatan for too long.
不要答應他的要求
Reject his request.
我還沒提出要求呢
Oh, I ain't requesting nothing.
- 問問我是誰 - 你是埃裏克·史蒂文斯
- Ask who I am. - You're Erik Stevens.
美國黑人間諜
An American black operative.
人稱克爾芒戈的傭兵
A mercenary nicknamed Killmonger.
這就是你的真是身份
That's who you are.
這可不是我的名字 公主
That's not my name, Princess.
問我啊 國王
Ask me, King.
不
No.
快問我
Ask me.
把他帶下去
Take him away.
你到底是誰？
Who are you?
我是恩賈達卡 恩喬布王子之子
I am N'Jadaka, son of Prince N'Jobu.
恩喬布之子
Son of N'Jobu?
我父親死的時候
I found my daddy
胸前可是有豹子爪印
with Panther claws in his chest!
你不是什麼國王的兒子 你就是一個兇手的兒子
You ain't the son of a king. You a son of a murderer.
你撒謊
You're lying!
- 一派胡言！ - 恐怕他說的是真的 母后
- Lies! - I'm afraid not, Queen Mother.
什麼
What?
恩喬布的後代
The descendent of N'Jobu.
你好啊 伯母
Hey, Auntie.
我現在行使我作為王族後裔的權利
I'm exercising my blood right
向王位發出挑戰
to challenge for the mantles of king...
挑戰黑豹
and Black Panther.
別接受他的挑戰 特查拉
Do not do this, T'Challa.
身為恩喬布王子的後裔
As the son of Prince N'Jobu,
他有這個權利
he is within his rights.
他在這裏沒有任何權利
He has no rights here!
挑戰要做數周的準備工作
The challenge will take weeks to prepare.
數周？ 我不需要這麼久
Weeks? I don't need weeks.
我不需要整個國家在場 我只需要他
The whole country ain't gotta be there. I just need him.
以及一個可以幫我鬆綁的人
And somebody to get me outta these chains.
特查拉 你想清楚了嗎？
T'Challa, what do you know of this?
我接受你的挑戰
I accept your challenge.
他不可能打敗特查拉的
He'll never beat T'Challa.
他就應該在上次挑戰的時候來
He should've just come to the first challenge
一次性搞定
and gotten it over with.
國王現將
The king will now have the strength
黑豹之力移除
of the Black Panther stripped away.
羅斯探員在哪
Where is Agent Ross?
我把他關在辦公室了 他跑不了的
I locked him in the office. He's not going anywhere.
這是你最後的機會
This is your last chance.
放下武器
Throw down your weapons,
這樣我們還有商量的餘地
and we can handle this another way.
我的一生都在為這一時刻做準備
I lived my entire life waitin' for this moment.
我艱苦訓練 謊話連天 殺人無數
I trained, I lied, I killed...
就是為了到這裏
just to get here.
我征戰過美國 阿富汗
I killed in America, Afghanistan...
伊拉克
Iraq.
我剝奪生命
I took life from my own brothers and sisters
剝奪來自這片陸地的兄弟姐妹們的生命
right here on this continent.
殺了這麼多人
And all this death...
就只是為了殺你
just so I could kill you.
挑戰現在開始
Let the challenge begin.
投降！
Yield!
幹掉他 特查拉！
Snap out of it, T'Challa!
快啊 站起來
Come on, get up.
來啊
Come here.
這是為了我的父親
This is for my father.
埃裏克！
Erik!
- 祖瑞 不 - 住手
- Zuri, no. - Stop!
- 祖瑞 - 祖瑞 不
- Zuri! - Zuri, don't!
是我讓你的父親喪命
I am the cause of your father's death.
不是他
Not him.
殺我
Take me.
你們倆都要死 詹姆斯叔叔
I'll take you both, Uncle James.
不！
No!
不！ 不！
No! No!
祖瑞 不
Zuri, no!
不！
No!
不 不！祖瑞！ 祖瑞！
No! No! Zuri! Zuri!
不！ 不！
No! No!
這就是你們的國王？
Is this your king? Huh?
Is this your king?
黑豹
The Black Panther,
本應是帶領你們走向未來的人
who's supposed to lead you into the future?
加油 哥哥！
Come on, Brother!
真的沒有辦法了嗎？
Is there nothing that can be done?
就他？
Him?
還想保護你們？
He's supposed to protect you?
- 不要 - 不要
- No. - No!
不！
No!
不 我才是你們的王
Nah. I'm your king.
- 不！ - 我們得馬上離開
- No! No! - We have to go now!
母后 我們走！
Queen Mother, let's go!
太后和舒莉 她們安全嗎？
The Queen Mother and Shuri, they are safe?
安全
Yes.
謝謝你
Thank you.
我們得馬上去找她們
We should get to them immediately.
我不能
I cannot
什麼？
What?
去吧 我的心和你在一起
Though my heart is with you.
我們不能把我們的國家
We cannot turn over our nation to a man
交給一個才出現了幾個小時的人
who showed up here only hours ago.
他有皇室血統
He is of royal blood.
- 他殺了特查拉！ - 那是在格鬥儀式中
- He killed T'Challa! - In ritual combat.
那還不是一樣？
Does that really matter?
你是瓦坎達最出色的戰士
You are the greatest warrior Wakanda has.
幫我在他強大起來之前推翻他
Help me overthrow him before he becomes too strong.
推翻？
Overthrow?
娜奇雅
Nakia!
我不是那種來去隨意的間諜
I'm not a spy who can come and go as they so choose!
我所效忠的是那個王座 不管是誰坐在上面
I am loyal to that throne, no matter who sits upon it.
你效忠的是什麼？
What are you loyal to?
我愛他
I loved him.
我也愛我的國家
I loved my country, too.
那你就應該效忠你的國家
Then you serve your country.
不 我要拯救我的國家
No. I save my country.
出什麼事了
What's wrong?
國王死了
The king is dead.
你要不想跟他為伍就跟我走
Come with me, unless you want to join him.
先是爸爸
First Baba.
現在輪到我的哥哥
And now my brother.
媽媽 我們甚至都沒能安葬他
Mama, we didn't even get to bury him.
- 是我 - 娜奇雅 這人是誰？
- It's me. - Nakia. Who is this man?
他是特查拉的朋友 他救過我的命
He's a friend of T'Challa's. He saved my life.
奧科燁呢？
Where's Okoye?
奧科燁沒有來
Okoye is not coming.
她和多拉米拉吉護衛隊會效忠新王
She and the Dora Milaje will serve the new king.
在這等我
Wait here.
我們的瓦坎達怎麼了
What has happened to our Wakanda?
讓心形草
Allow the Heart-Shaped Herb...
賦予你黑豹的力量
to give you the powers of the Black Panther...
帶你前往先祖的世界
and take you to the Ancestral Plane.
我怎麼跟你說的 別翻我的東西
What did I tell you about going into my things?
你找到了什麼
What did you find?
你的家
Your home.
我給你鑰匙 就是希望你有一天能看到它
I gave you a key hoping that you might see it someday.
沒錯 那裏的日落
Yes. The sunsets there
是全世界最美的
are the most beautiful in the world.
但我擔心你不會受歡迎
But I fear you still may not be welcome.
為什麼？
Why?
他們會說你走丟了
They will say you are lost.
但我就在這裏啊
But I'm right here.
不為我流淚嗎
No tears for me?
每個人都難逃一死
Everybody dies.
這裏的生活就是這樣
It's just life around here.
瞧瞧我都做了些什麼
Well, look at what I have done.
我早就該帶你回去的
I should've taken you back long ago.
而現在 我們都被拋棄在這兒了
Instead, we are both abandoned here.
也許走丟了的是你的家才對
Well, maybe your home is the one that's lost.
所以他們才找不到我們
That's why they can't find us.
呼吸 呼吸 陛下 呼吸
Breathe! Breathe, My King, breathe.
呼吸 呼吸
Breathe. Breathe. Breathe.
是心形草的作用嗎
The Heart-Shaped Herb did that?
全部的都在這麼
This all of it?
當下一任國王繼位時
Yes. So when it comes time for another king,
我們就能準備好
we will be ready.
下一任國王？
Another king?
去把那些都燒了
Yeah, go ahead and burn all that.
陛下 我們不能這麼做 這是我們的傳統
My King, we cannot do that. It is our tradition...
我讓你做什麼 你就得做什麼
When I tell you to do something, I mean that shit.
全燒了
Burn it all!
你們知道麼 在我的家鄉
You know, where I'm from...
黑人鬧革命的時候
when black folks started revolutions,
他們沒有武器
they never had the firepower...
也沒有資源去反抗壓迫者
or the resources to fight their oppressors.
那時瓦坎達在哪裏呢？
Where was Wakanda?
這種局面以後將不復存在
Yeah, all that ends today.
我們在地球上每個國家裏都安插有間諜
We got spies embedded in every nation on Earth.
全都已經就位
Already in place.
我知道殖民者是怎麼想的
I know how colonizers think.
所以我們要以其人之道還治其人之身
So we're gonna use their own strategy against 'em.
我們會把振金武器送到我們的間諜手中
We're gonna send vibranium weapons out to our War Dogs.
他們會武裝全世界被壓迫的人民
They'll arm oppressed people all over the world...
這樣他們才能站起來反抗 殺掉掌權者
so they can finally rise up and kill those in power.
和他們的孩子
And their children.
以及所有他們的同夥
And anyone else who takes their side.
是時候向他們展示我們真正的實力了
It's time they know the truth about us!
我們是戰士
We're warriors!
世界秩序將被重新建立 而這一次 將由我們來掌權
The world's gonna start over, and this time, we're on top.
瓦坎達將成為日不落帝國
The sun will never set on the Wakandan empire.
瓦坎達之所以能在世界中存在這麼久
Wakanda has survived for so long...
正是因為我們只在絕對必要的時候才打仗
by fighting when only absolutely necessary.
瓦坎達過去是這樣的 沒錯
Wakanda survived in the past this way, yes.
但世界在改變啊 將軍
But the world is changing, General.
長老們 瓦坎達的優勢受到挑戰
Elders, it is getting smaller.
外面的世界正在迎頭趕上
The outside world is catching up...
不久之後 它要麼征服別人
and soon it will be the conquerors
要麼就被別人征服
or the conquered.
我寧願做征服者
I'd rather be the former.
你們聽到命令了 開始行動吧
You heard your orders. Let's get to it.
我們要去哪來著
So where are we going again?
我們要把心形草
We're taking the Heart-Shaped Herb
帶到賈巴裏的領地
to Jabariland.
心形草？ 那是什麼？
Heart-Shaped Herb? What is that?
它會增強服用者的能力
It gives whoever takes it heightened abilities.
正是它讓特查拉變得那麼強大的
It's what made T'Challa so strong.
娜奇雅
Nakia.
我不喜歡這樣
I don't like this.
心形草是屬於我們的
The Herb belongs to us.
我們這樣可能會讓姆巴庫成為更為可怕的惡魔
We may be creating a bigger monster with M'Baku.
娜奇雅 你應該給自己用
Nakia, you should take it yourself.
我只是個間諜 手上沒有軍隊
I am a spy with no army.
我一點機會都沒有的
I wouldn't stand a chance.
我們走吧
We'll go.
天哪
Oh, boy.
該死
Oh, shit.
低頭 冷靜
Look down. Stay calm.
舒莉
Shuri.
低頭
Look down.
我的兒子
My son...
在格鬥儀式中被謀殺了
was murdered in ritual combat.
- 格鬥的過程公平嗎 - 公平 但
- Were the odds fair? - Yes, but...
那就不是謀殺 而是戰敗
So it was less a murder than a defeat.
- 這輪不到你來說！- 安靜
- Do not rub our noses in it! - Silence!
這裏我說了算 小姑娘
I make the pronouncements here, girl.
聽我說 陛下 新王是一個...
Look, uh, Your Highness, the new king is a U.S...
新王...
The new king...
你不准說話
You cannot talk!
再多說一個字
One more word,
我就把你餵給我的孩子們
and I will feed you to my children.
開玩笑的 我們是素食主義者
I'm kidding. We are vegetarians.
偉大的人猿姆巴庫
Great Gorilla M'Baku...
這就是我們來這兒的原因
this is why we are here.
把這個獻給你
To offer this to you.
一個外來者坐在了我們的王位上
An outsider sits on our throne.
只有你能幫我們阻止他
Only you can help us stop him.
跟我來
Come with me.
這不可能
Impossible!
他還活著嗎
Is he breathing?
他昏迷了 只剩一口氣
He's in a coma. Barely clinging to life.
我們的一個漁夫
One of our fishermen found him
在河邊發現了他
at the edge of the river border.
並把他帶到了我這裏
He brought him to me.
為什麼把他埋在雪裏？
Why do you have him in the snow?
這是唯一
It is the only thing keeping him
能挽回他性命的辦法
from joining the ancestors.
我們得把他帶回實驗室 在那我就可以救活他
We need to get him to my lab. I can heal him there.
帶他走吧 他撐不了多久的
Take him. He'll be dead in seconds.
娜奇雅 草藥
Nakia, the Herb.
列祖列宗在上
I call upon the ancestors.
芭絲特女神在上
I call upon Bast.
吾與吾子 特查拉
I am here with my son, T'Challa.
拯救他
Heal him.
我們必須把他埋起來 蓋住他 蓋住他
We must bury him. Cover him. Cover him!
好的
Okay.
願祖上榮光永存
Praise the ancestors.
醒來吧 特查拉
Wake up, T'Challa.
醒來吧
Wake up.
我的兒子
My son.
時間到了 你是時候回家
The time has come for you to come home...
與我團聚了
and be reunited with me.
為什麼
Why?
為什麼你不帶那個男孩回家？
Why didn't you bring the boy home?
為什麼 爸爸？
Why, Baba?
他...
He...
我選擇忽略掉這一事實
He was the truth I chose to omit.
你不應該拋棄他的
You were wrong to abandon him.
我選擇了我的人民
I chose my people.
我選擇了瓦坎達
I chose Wakanda.
我們的未來決定於...
Our future depended...
你錯了！
You were wrong!
你們全都錯了！
All of you were wrong!
錯就錯在我們對於外面的世界視而不見
To turn your backs on the rest of the world!
對外面世界的恐懼
We let the fear of our discovery
阻礙了我們做出正確的選擇
stop us from doing what is right!
不能再這樣下去了！
No more!
我不能和你待在這
I cannot stay here with you.
只要他還坐在王座上我就不能安息
I cannot rest while he sits on the throne.
他是我們自己創造出來的怪物
He is a monster of our own making.
我必須要奪回王位 我一定要！
I must take the mantle back. I must!
我必須糾正這些錯誤
I must right these wrongs.
可以給我個毯子嗎？
Do you have a blanket?
克爾芒戈獲得了
Killmonger has the full support
軍隊的全力支持
of our military.
而且...
And he burned the garden of the Heart-Shaped Herb.
他還把心形草全都燒光了
Of course he did.
他當然會 他就是被這麼訓練的
That's what he was trained to do.
他的組織曾經和中情局合作
His unit used to work with the CIA
在別國製造混亂
to destabilize foreign countries.
他們總是在政權交替時趁人之危
They would always strike at transitions of power...
比如大選年 或部族首領死亡
like an election year, or the death of a monarch.
他們就掌控政府 軍隊
You get control of government, the military...
- 衝著我們的資源來的 - 沒錯
- Our resources. - Right.
我們偉大的部落
The Great Mound.
我們的振金 我的發明
Our vibranium, all of my designs.
他會把我們的武器送到世界各地
He will send our weapons all over the world.
你必須護送她們安全離開瓦坎達
You must get them out of Wakanda safely.
- 什麼？ - 那你呢？
- What? - What about you?
挑戰必須繼續
The challenge will have to continue.
特查拉 我們不會離開瓦坎達的
T'Challa, we will not leave Wakanda.
保護你的安全是我的責任
It is my duty to keep you safe.
如果他掌控了我們的技術
If he gets control of our technology,
我們無處可逃
nowhere will be safe.
黑豹還活著
The Black Panther lives.
而等他為瓦坎達的命運戰鬥時
And when he fights for the fate of Wakanda...
我將在他身邊
I will be right there beside him.
我也是
As will I.
我也加入
I'm in, too.
怎麼 人多力量大嘛
What? You're gonna need all the help you can get.
你們完事了沒？
Are you done?
你們到底完事了沒有？
可以讓我跟姆巴庫首領單獨談談嗎？
Could you give me and Lord M'Baku a moment?
謝謝你
Thank you.
我欠你的
I owed you a great debt.
一命抵一命
A life for a life.
你我就兩清了
Consider it paid.
請允許我母親留在你這裏
Please allow my mother to stay here.
她不會有事的 我向你保證
No harm will come to her. I give you my word.
你知道 我也能帶兵打仗的
You know, I could use an army as well.
你當然能
I bet you could.
但沒門
But no.
我不會讓賈巴裏人為你的事賣命
I will give no Jabari lives towards your cause.
這是我們的事
It is our cause.
- 是我們共同的事 - 我們？
- It is for all of us. - Oh, us?
我們？ 你是幾個世紀以來第一個來我們這的王
Us? You are the first king to come here in centuries...
現在你跟我說 「我們」？
and now you speak of "us"?
我無法替先王們開脫
I cannot speak for past kings.
但如今一個敵人正坐在王位上
But an enemy sits on the throne right now.
你我都知道振金的威力
We both know the power of vibranium.
如果克爾芒戈掌控了它
If Killmonger gains control of it,
你覺得他下一個會找上誰？
who do you think he will come for next?
我們不會幫你
We will not help you.
一切都在按計劃進行
Everything is on schedule.
間諜們都接到通知了嗎？
Have the spies been alerted?
是的 有一些間諜對於我們的新任務表示反對
Yes. Some resistance to our new mission.
但倫敦 紐約 和香港的間諜組織
But the War Dogs in London,
都隨時待命
New York and Hong Kong are standing by.
我們先攻打那些地方
We'll strike there first.
其他人會審時度勢的
The others'll come around.
看看這個
Look at this.
這個手持超音速炮的威力
A handheld sonic cannon,
足以對抗坦克
powerful enough to stop a tank...
金屬探測器都追查不到
untraceable by metal detectors.
而且我們有幾千個
And we got thousands of them.
世界終將明白我們的真正實力
The world's gonna find out exactly who we are.
他還活著
He lives.
恩賈達卡
N'Jadaka!
你想怎樣？
Wassup?
我還沒投降！
I never yielded!
而且如你所見 我也沒死！
And as you can see, I am not dead!
挑戰什麼的已經結束了
All that challenge shit is over with!
現在我是王
I'm the king now!
讓飛機起飛 繼續任務
Get those planes in the air! Carry out the mission!
- 舒莉 就現在 - 收到
- Shuri, now. - Copy that.
快走  快走 快點 羅斯
Go, go, go! Come on, Ross!
維卡必 幹掉這隻小丑
W'Kabi, man, kill this clown.
維卡必 挑戰還沒結束
W'Kabi, the challenge is not complete.
我們該怎麼辦
What will we do?
邊疆部落
Border Tribe!
你！
You!
你的心中怨氣太深
Your heart is so full of hatred...
你不適合當王！
you are not fit to be a king!
來吧
Come on!
阿尤 保護國王
Ayo, the king!
防禦陣型
Shields!
維卡必 停下來！
W'Kabi, stop this!
快停下！
Stop this now!
不！
No!
娜奇雅和我將會用這個控制皇家戰機
Nakia and I will get control of the Royal Talon with this.
那麼 我做什麼
So what do I do?
你要駕駛它
You'll have to fly it.
- 什麼？ - 你曾是個厲害的飛行員
- What? - You were a great pilot.
不用擔心 我會指導你的
Don't worry, I'll guide you through it.
就像開摩托飛艇一樣
It's just like riding a hoverbike.
什麼？ 你們還有摩托飛艇嗎？
What? You guys have hoverbikes?
嘿 娜奇雅 穿上這個
Hey, Nakia, take that.
- 我又不是戰士 - 就穿上吧 這是戰甲！
- I'm not a Dora. - Just put it on, it's armor!
快來
Come!
祝你好運 羅斯探員
Good luck, Agent Ross!
我不知道該怎麼用...這個東西
Yeah, I don't know what I'm doing with this.
我們都指望你了
We're counting on you.
瓦坎達萬歲
Wakanda forever.
上啊！
Come on!
快走
Go, go!
遠程駕駛系統啟動
Remote piloting system activated.
天啊
My God.
我幫你改成美式機艙了 快坐進去
I made it American style for you. Get in.
好吧
All right.
好！
Yes!
快上 我們不能讓那些武器出了瓦坎達的邊境
Go! We can't let those weapons get beyond Wakanda.
好的 我馬上
All right, I'm on it.
鎖住！
Lock!
拿下
Get him down!
摘掉他的項鏈
Get the necklace!
摘掉他的項鏈！
瓦坎達萬歲！
Wakanda forever!
好了 舒莉 我追到他們了 我該怎麼做？
Okay, Shuri. I got 'em. What do I do?
把他們打下來啊 天才！
Shoot them down, genius!
好吧
All right.
我盡力而為吧
Here goes nothing.
好了 一架
All right, got them.
該死
Oh, shit.
Shit, shit, shit.
漂亮
Nice!
舒莉！
Shuri!
怎麼了 公主？
What's up, Princess?
你永遠成不了真正的王
You'll never be a true king.
哥哥！
Brother!
舒莉
Shuri.
哥哥！
Brother!
把最底下的火車開起來
Turn on the train on the bottom track.
穩定器會讓你的戰衣失效的的
The stabilizers will deactivate your suit!
你到時候就沒有保護了
You won't have protection!
那他也不會有
Neither will he.
好吧
Okay!
我根本不需要這身衣服來殺你
I don't need a suit to kill you.
你的統治結束了
Your reign is over!
你以為你能穩居王位
You sat up here, safe and protected.
你就是想看著我們
You want to see us become
變成那些你憎恨的人一樣
just like the people you hate so much.
就像那些殖民者一樣
Divide and conquer the land as they did!
不 這是我從敵人那兒學到的 以牙還牙
Nah, I learn from my enemies. Beat them at they own game.
你已經變得跟他們一樣！
You have become them!
你會毀了這世界的 包括瓦坎達在內
You will destroy the world, Wakanda included!
這個世界奪走了我的一切！
The world took everything away from me!
一切我所愛的東西！
Everything I ever loved!
但是我會確保人人平等
But I'mma make sure we're even.
我要找到所有
I'mma track down anyone who would
哪怕對你只有一絲忠誠的人！
even think about being loyal to you!
全都宰了埋了
And I'm gonna put they ass in the dirt
就埋在祖瑞的邊上！
right next to Zuri!
娜奇雅！
Nakia!
- 你沒事吧？ - 我沒事 你呢？
- Are you all right? - I'm okay. You?
- 沒事 - 我們走
- Yes. - Let's go.
舒莉 我甩掉了一架敵機 但是還有兩架在我屁股後面
Shuri, I've lost one of them, but two are on my tail.
什麼鬼？
Shit. What the hell was that?
實驗室正遭受攻擊
The lab is under attack.
什麼？ 哪？
What? Where?
停止全息影像
Deactivating hologram.
羅斯 你必須馬上離開那
Ross, you have to get out of there, now!
我還剩多久時間？
How long have I got?
玻璃完整度 50%
Glass integrity is at 50%.
把我接回去
Put me back in.
羅斯！羅斯！
Ross! Ross!
馬上投降！
Surrender now!
你有三秒鐘放下你的武器
You have three seconds to lay down your weapon!
一！
One!
二！
Two!
讓你們見識見識賈巴裏的力量吧！
Witness the might of the Jabari firsthand!
玻璃完整度 15%
Glass integrity is at 15%.
- 武器嚴重損毀 - 該死
- Critical weapons failure. - Shit!
舒莉 最後一艘貨船
Hey, Shuri! The last cargo ship
就快到邊境了
is almost at the border...
他們現在用某種電纜把我困住了
but they got me trapped with some kind of cables.
把雙手交叉放在胸前
Make an X with your arms!
音速超頻啟動
Sonic Overload initiated.
現在 放開
Now break it!
五秒後重啟系統...
System rebooting in five...
4 3
four, three...
2 1
two, one.
系統重啟完成
System rebooted.
耶！ 我們成功了！
Yes! We did it!
太好了 現在趕緊離開那
Great! Now get out of there!
沖
Charge!
放下你的武器
Drop your weapon!
你會殺了我嗎 親愛的？
Would you kill me, my love?
為了瓦坎達？
For Wakanda?
毫無疑問
Without question!
到此為止了 表弟
This is it for you, Cousin.
有兩下子啊
Hell of a move!
爸爸說
My pop said Wakanda was
瓦坎達是他見過最美麗的地方
the most beautiful thing he ever seen.
他答應我 說總有一天他會帶我去看看
He promised he was gonna show it to me one day.
你能相信嗎
You believe that?
一個奧克蘭的小屁孩
Kid from Oakland,
整天活在童話故事裏
running around believing in fairy tales.
真的很美
It's beautiful.
也許我們還能治好你
Maybe we can still heal you.
為什麼？
Why?
然後你就可以把我關起來？
So you can just lock me up?
才不要
Nah.
把我葬在海裏
Just bury me in the ocean...
就像我那些從船上跳海的先祖們一樣
with my ancestors that jumped from the ships.
因為他們知道死也比被奴役好
'Cause they knew death was better than bondage.
謝謝
Thank you.
你救了我
You saved me.
你救了我的家人
You saved my family.
我們的國家
Our nation.
你不用謝我什麼
There's nothing to thank me for.
這是我們的...
It is our duty to...
為我愛的事物去戰鬥是我的義務
It was my duty to fight for what I love.
我就應該...
I should've...
你不能怪我 我差點就死了
You can't blame me, I almost died.
留下
Stay.
我想我有個辦法
I think I know a way
仍可以讓你實現你的願望
you can still fulfill your calling.
留下吧
Please stay.
他要上籃了 他要上籃了
Oh, he moves it! He moves it!
- 誰負責防守他的 - 進了
- Who man is that? - Bucket!
小菜一碟
Easy.
你之前說
When you said you would take me
要帶我到加州
to California for the first time...
我還以為你指的是讓我參加科切拉音樂節
I thought you meant Coachella...
或者是迪士尼樂園
or Disneyland.
為什麼是這裏？
Why here?
這就是我們的父親殺了我們叔叔的地方
This is where our father killed our uncle.
這裏要被拆掉了
They're tearing it down.
很好
Good.
這裏不會被拆掉的
They are not tearing it down.
我買下了這棟樓
I bought this building.
還有那棟
And that building.
以及那邊那棟
And that one over there.
這裏將成為第一個
This will be the first
瓦坎達國際援助中心
Wakandan International Outreach Center.
娜奇雅會負責監管社會援助
Nakia will oversee the social outreach.
而你會負責進行
And you will spearhead
第一次科學與信息交流活動
the science and information exchange.
你在逗我嗎
You're kidding.
有嗎？
Eh?
嘿哥們 那是什麼
Hey, yo. Man, what the hell is that?
這是布加迪牌的宇宙飛船吧
That's like a Bugatti spaceship!
就這麼憑空出現了 你看到了嗎？
Bro, it came out of nowhere. Did y'all see that?
什麼？
What?
快來看啊
Check it out, bro.
把這個帶回家呀
We can take this back to the house.
開著這個去上學啊
Pull up to school in this.
嘿 聽著 我們可以把這個給拆了然後賣掉
Look, we can break it apart. We can sell it.
在淘寶上賣
On eBay.
一片就能賣上個幾十萬
Everybody get, like, a million apiece.
我如果是你們我就不會這麼做
I wouldn't do that if I were you guys.
- 你從哪來的？ - 瓦坎達
- Where you come from? - From Wakanda.
瓦坎達是哪？
What is a Wakanda?
嘿 你！
Hey, yo!
這是你的？
This yours?
你...
Who...
你是誰？
Who are you?
我是國王特查拉
My name is King T'Challa...
特查卡國王之子
son of King T'Chaka.
我是瓦坎達的最高統治者
I am the sovereign ruler of the nation of Wakanda.
這是我們有史以來第一次
And for the first time in our history...
與外界分享交流
we will be sharing our knowledge and resources...
我們的知識和資源
with the outside world.
瓦坎達不再會置身於幕後
Wakanda will no longer watch from the shadows.
我們不能
We cannot.
我們也不應該
We must not.
我們將努力成為一個榜樣
We will work to be an example of how we...
向世人展示 如何像對待兄弟姐妹一樣
as brothers and sisters on this earth...
對待地球上的同胞
should treat each other.
今昔不比往日
Now, more than ever...
分裂的假象威脅著我們的存在
the illusions of division threaten our very existence.
我們都知道真相
We all know the truth.
我們的共同點遠大於我們的分歧點
More connects us than separates us.
但是在危機時刻
But in times of crisis...
智者將建立橋樑
the wise build bridges...
而愚者則建立高牆
while the foolish build barriers.
我們必須達成共識
We must find a way...
同舟共濟
to look after one another...
構建人類命運共同體
as if we were one, single tribe.
恕我直言 國王特查拉
With all due respect, King T'Challa...
你們一個農耕國家
what can a nation of farmers
能向全世界貢獻什麼呢？
have to offer the rest of the world?
你們又在那個人的旁邊胡鬧吧
Are you playing around with that man again?
- 沒有 - 你又在逗他了
- No. - You're teasing him again.
- 別吵醒他 他需要休息 - 我沒有
- Don't wake him. He must rest. - No, I'm not.
我沒有
No, I'm not.
塔博 就是你幹的
Thabo, you're doing that.
是他幹的 他撒謊
He's doing it. He's lying.
不要鬧了 他在休息呢
No, he's resting.
去玩吧
Go, go!
白狼
White Wolf!
別鬧了
Stop that!
白狼
White Wolf!
早上好 巴恩斯中士
Good morning, Sergeant Barnes.
叫我巴基就行
Bucky.
你感覺如何
How are you feeling?
挺好的
Good.
謝謝你
Thank you.
跟我來
Come.
你要學的東西還有很多
Much more for you to learn.